<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kerberos on edermi's Blog</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/tags/kerberos/</link><description>Recent content in Kerberos on edermi's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</managingEditor><webMaster>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 20:55:36 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edermi.github.io/tags/kerberos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Abusing accounts that already changed their password</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/post/2020/abusing_accounts_that_changed_passwords/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</author><guid>https://edermi.github.io/post/2020/abusing_accounts_that_changed_passwords/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>TL;DR&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>: &lt;em>In some circumstances, you may find usable Kerberos TGTs on a system you compromised - these allow you to impersonate a user that already changed its password (e.g. because the user got suspicious or a PAM solution is in place).&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>On a recent project, I was tasked with the usual goal: Start from the ground and find a way to take over the company - in the end, if possible, somehow become Domain Admin.
Getting started was tough, but after some time I got my hands on a few admin accounts and had a way to take control of the Domain Admins - but the way involved resetting the password of a service account.
Unless I do not have a very good reason to perform the password change or the explicit &amp;ldquo;Do it!&amp;rdquo; from the customer, I prefer finding another way.
Lurking for a few days on the machines I gained access so far, I discovered two accounts that logged on recently.
They both provided a simpler way to become Domain Admin because they were allowed to write the Domain Admin group directly - Jackpot!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>