<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Disclosure on edermi's Blog</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/tags/disclosure/</link><description>Recent content in Disclosure on edermi's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</managingEditor><webMaster>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 20:25:47 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edermi.github.io/tags/disclosure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vulnerabilities on vmwareidentity.de (XSS) and in VMware UEM (exportable authentication certificate)</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/post/2021/vmware_vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</author><guid>https://edermi.github.io/post/2021/vmware_vulnerabilities/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is a short notice about vulnerabilities in VMware products I found earlier this year.
During a penetration test of a freshly built environment, I took a closer look at VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) in combination with devices enrolled and managed via VMware Unified Endpoint Management (UEM).
I found a reflected XSS vulnerability on VMware&amp;rsquo;s authenticator &lt;code>vmwareidentity.de&lt;/code> that can be abused by sending links to unauthenticated victims.
Also, I found it possible to export a user&amp;rsquo;s authentication certificate, which allows to access zero trust protected resources without access to the user&amp;rsquo;s device or account on a trusted system.
There has been no advisory or notification for affected customers I am aware of.
The disclosure deadline was already a few weeks ago and VMware did not respond to multiple attempts of contacting them as well as offering an extension of the responsible disclosure timeframe, therefore I am releasing the vulnerability details to the public.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>