<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>red team on edermi's Blog</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/tags/red-team/</link><description>Recent content in red team on edermi's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</managingEditor><webMaster>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://edermi.github.io/tags/red-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vulnerabilities on vmwareidentity.de (XSS) and in VMware UEM (exportable authentication certificate)</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/post/2021/vmware_vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</author><guid>https://edermi.github.io/post/2021/vmware_vulnerabilities/</guid><description>This post is a short notice about vulnerabilities in VMware products I found earlier this year. During a penetration test of a freshly built environment, I took a closer look at VMware Unified Access Gateway (UAG) in combination with devices enrolled and managed via VMware Unified Endpoint Management (UEM). I found a reflected XSS vulnerability on VMware&amp;rsquo;s authenticator vmwareidentity.de that can be abused by sending links to unauthenticated victims. Also, I found it possible to export a user&amp;rsquo;s authentication certificate, which allows to access zero trust protected resources without access to the user&amp;rsquo;s device or account on a trusted system.</description></item><item><title>Modding Gophish</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/post/2021/modding_gophish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</author><guid>https://edermi.github.io/post/2021/modding_gophish/</guid><description>TL;DR: I&amp;rsquo;ll shine a light on Gophish and how to modify it to change behavior or introduce/remove functionality. At the end of this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll know how to host custom 404 pages in Gophish and how to abuse HTTP basic auth instead of login forms embedded on the landing page to obtain juicy creds.
A few days ago I tweeted one of my modifications to Gophish:
After low click rates in my last phishing campaign due to staff being extremely well trained for this kind of attack, I modded gophish to show an HTTP Basic auth request instead of a phishing site.</description></item><item><title>Abusing accounts that already changed their password</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/post/2020/abusing_accounts_that_changed_passwords/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</author><guid>https://edermi.github.io/post/2020/abusing_accounts_that_changed_passwords/</guid><description>TL;DR: In some circumstances, you may find usable Kerberos TGTs on a system you compromised - these allow you to impersonate a user that already changed its password (e.g. because the user got suspicious or a PAM solution is in place).
Intro On a recent project, I was tasked with the usual goal: Start from the ground and find a way to take over the company - in the end, if possible, somehow become Domain Admin.</description></item><item><title>Passing the hash with native RDP client (mstsc.exe)</title><link>https://edermi.github.io/post/2018/native_rdp_pass_the_hash/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>spam-blog@michael-eder.net (Michael Eder)</author><guid>https://edermi.github.io/post/2018/native_rdp_pass_the_hash/</guid><description>TL;DR: If the remote server allows Restricted Admin login, it is possible to login via RDP by passing the hash using the native Windows RDP client mstsc.exe. (You&amp;rsquo;ll need mimikatz or something else to inject the hash into the process)
On engagements it is usually only a matter of time to get your hands on NTLM hashes. These can usually be directly used to authenticate against other services / machines and enable lateral movement.</description></item></channel></rss>